ere.net 2019-06-07

# Privacy Policy - ERE Media

### ERE MEDIA, INC. PRIVACY POLICY

Last updated: May 16, 2018

##### 1\. INTRODUCTION

At ERE Media, Inc. we take your privacy rights, and your expectation of privacy, very seriously.  Our Privacy Policy has changed significantly, and we strongly encourage you to read the policy and to let us know if you have any questions

This Privacy Policy describes ERE Media’s policies and procedures regarding the collection, use and disclosure of information which you provide when you use ERE Media’s [_eretraining.com_](http://www.eretraining.com/) _,_[ _ere.net_](https://www.ere.net/) _,_[ _sourcecon.com_](https://www.sourcecon.com/) _._[ _tlnt.com_](https://www.tlnt.com/) _,_[ _eremedia.com_](https://www.eremedia.com/), and ERE Media conference-related web sites (the “Web Sites”), when you use the related services and features offered on the Web Sites, and when you subscribe to, register for ERE Media’s conferences and webinars (the Web Sites, the related services and features, including ERE Media’s mobile and digital applications, the conferences and webinars, and any other products and/or services offered by ERE Media are collectively referred to as the “ERE Media Products”).

ERE Media will not use or share your information obtained through your use of the ERE Media Products for any purpose or with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.  However, please note that this Privacy Policy does not apply to information we collect by other means or from other sources.

##### 2\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR INFORMATION

**Information You Provide**. When you access the Web Sites, subscribe to, register for or participate in conferences or webinars, use mobile or digital applications, participate in social networking, enter contests or surveys, make purchases of any ERE Media Products, or at other times, we collect and store personally identifiable information (generally defined to mean information that can be used on its own or with other information to identify, contact or locate a single person, or identify an individual in context) about you that may include, your name, postal and e-mail addresses, professional affiliation, information regarding your computer system, and other information.

We request certain information from you if you make a payment from one of our Web Sites. You must provide contact information, such as your e-mail address, and payment information, such as a credit/debit card number and the expiration date. Payment information is used for payment processing purposes only.   We use a credit/debit card processing company to process credit/debit card charges for ERE Media Products.  We do not retain, share, store or use credit/debit card information for any secondary purposes (subject to Federal, state law including the California Public Records Act, and applicable non-US law such as the European Union’s General Data Privacy Regulation, or “GDPR”) and will exercise reasonable care, but no less than the care required by applicable laws, to prevent disclosure or use of credit/debit card information.

**Information Provided By Third Parties**. We may from time to time obtain information about you from third-parties such as business partners, mobile carriers or other companies. If you use your login credentials from a social networking site (“SNS”) to use an ERE Media Product, we may receive information from such SNS in accordance with the terms and conditions of the SNS.  We may use any information about you which we receive from a third party to include in our database(s) or append to existing user data to add more detail to the information we have about you.

**Cookies**.  For each visitor to our Web sites, our web server may automatically attempt to identify the user through a cookie placed within the user’s web browser (a cookie is a message given to a [web browser](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/B/browser.html) by a [web server](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/W/Web_server.html); the browser stores the message in a [text file](http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/T/text_file.html); the message is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server).  This is done to provide users with more relevant access to the Web Sites. From time to time we may also track information, in aggregate, on pages and features that users access or view. The activity is collected and stored in our server’s log files. We may log Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, or the location of your computer on the Internet, for systems administration and troubleshooting purposes. We use this information in an aggregate fashion to track access to the Web Sites.  Our email alerts utilize tracking technology that allows us to see how many newsletter e-mails are opened and the e-mail address of users who have clicked on a given story, feature or advertisement. We use this information for internal purposes, to measure the aggregate number of people who view a given newsletter item.

We may also place cookies on users’ computers to allow users to store login information, personalize their user experience and navigate easily through the Web Sites. Through the use of additional cookies or technology, we will have the ability to track users by their behavior profile and geographic location for the purpose of pushing advertising that matches their interests and/or specific location.  We, or the service provider, will inform you of such collection at the time you use the service.  By giving your consent, you agree to our collection, use and disclosure of your location information as described.

**Third Party Advertisements**. We may use third-party advertising service vendors to serve advertisements on the ERE Media Products. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal information such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and we disclaim all liability in connection therewith.  For more information about third-party ad networks that use these technologies, and to opt-out of their collection of information, see <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp> and <http://www.aboutads.info/consumers>.  You may have additional rights regarding opt-out of third party advertising services, including those set forth below, if you reside in a jurisdiction such as the European Economic Area which provides for enhanced user rights.

##### 3\. HOW WE PROCESS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

The following sets forth the ways we process your personal information.  For residents of the European Economic Area, this disclosure is required by GDPR Articles 13 and 14.  GDPR also requires us to inform you that the legal basis for processing this information is, as applicable, your consent, our legitimate interest, or a contract we have entered into with you.

(a) We may process information about your use of the ERE Media Products (“usage data”). The usage data may include your IP address, geographical location, browser type and version, operating system, referral source, length of visit, page views and website navigation paths, as well as information about the timing, frequency and pattern of your use of the ERE Media Products. We use this usage data for the purposes of analyzing your use of the ERE Media Products.

(b) We may process your account information (“account data”). The account data may include your name and email address. We use this account data to provide the ERE Media Products to you, maintain back-ups of our databases and communicate with you.

(c) We may process your information which you have included in your personal profile on our websites (“profile data”). The profile data may include your name, address, telephone number, email address, profile pictures, date of birth, educational details and employment details. We use this profile data to enable and monitor your use of the ERE Media Products.

(d) We may process information that you post on our Web Sites or through our services (“publication data”). We use this publication data enable the posts and to administer the ERE Media Products.

(e) We may process information contained in any enquiry you submit to us regarding the ERE Media Products (“enquiry data”).  We use this enquiry date for the purposes of offering, marketing and selling relevant goods and/or services to you.

(f) We may process information relating to transactions, including purchases of goods and services, that you enter into with us and/or through ERE Media (“transaction data”). The transaction data may include your contact details, your payment card details and the transaction details. We use this transaction data for the purpose of supplying the purchased goods and services to you and keeping proper records of those transactions.

(g) We may process information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our email notifications and/or newsletters and downloading ERE Media or third party white papers (“notification data”). We use this notification data for the purposes of sending you relevant notifications, newsletters and/or white papers.

(h) We may process information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us (“correspondence data”). The correspondence data may include the communication content and metadata associated with the communication. Our Web Site will generate the metadata associated with communications made using the website contact forms. We use this correspondence data for the purposes of communicating with you and record-keeping.

(i) We may process any of your personal information where necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure, and where necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, or obtaining professional advice.

(j) In addition to the specific purposes for which we may process your personal information set forth in this Privacy Policy, we may also process any of your personal information where such processing is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person.

##### 4\. PROVIDING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION TO OTHERS

The following sets forth the ways we may disclose your personal information to others.

(a) We may disclose personal information to our suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary to maintain the ERE Media Products.

(b) Financial transactions relating to ERE Media Products may be handled by our payment services providers.  We will share transaction data with our payment services providers only to the extent necessary for the purposes of processing your payments, refunding such payments and dealing with complaints and queries relating to such payments and refunds. At your request we will inform you of the identity of our payment service providers and provide links to their privacy policies and practices.

(c) We may disclose your enquiry data to one or more select third party suppliers of goods and services for the purpose of enabling them to contact you so that they can offer, market and sell to you relevant goods and/or services. Each such third party will act as a data controller in relation to the enquiry data that we supply to it; and upon contacting you, each such third party will supply to you a copy of its own privacy policy, which will govern that third party’s use of your personal information.

(d) We may disclose your personal information to our insurers and/or professional advisers insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes of obtaining or maintaining insurance coverage, managing risks, obtaining professional advice, or the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

(e) We may transfer part or all of your information in the case of a merger, acquisition, bankruptcy, or other sale of all or a portion of ERE Media’s assets or stock.

(f) In addition to the specific disclosures of personal information set out in this Section, we may disclose your personal information where such disclosure is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation to which we are subject, or in order to protect your vital interests or the vital interests of another natural person. We may also disclose your personal information where such disclosure is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims, whether in court proceedings or in an administrative or out-of-court procedure.

##### 5\. OTHER DISCLOSURES OF YOUR INFORMATION

We may store personal information in locations outside the direct control of ERE Media (for instance, on servers or databases co-located with hosting providers).

As we develop our business, we may buy or sell assets or business offerings.  Customer, email, and visitor information is generally one of the transferred business assets in these types of transactions. We may also transfer or assign such information in the course of corporate divestitures, mergers, or dissolution.   In such cases we cannot control acquiring parties’ use of your information.

We may disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety of any person; to address fraud, security or technical issues; or to protect ERE Media’s rights or property.

Additional use of your personal information that is not described in this Privacy Policy will only take place as required by statute or when we have obtained your consent.

##### 6\. LINKS TO OTHER WEB SITES

The ERE Media Products may contain links to other web sites or services that may be subject to less stringent privacy standards. ERE Media cannot assume any responsibility for the privacy practices, policies or actions of the third parties that operate these websites or services.  We are not responsible for how such third parties collect, use or disclose your personal information. You should review their privacy policies before providing them with personal information.

##### 7\. YOUR RIGHT TO OPT OUT

We are committed to providing users of ERE Media Products with the choice to receive or not receive e-mails, promotional materials and/or other communications from ERE Media. We only send commercial emails to users who have requested or consented to receive emails about our services and products. We do not send unsolicited commercial emails (“spam”), buy or sell email lists, or use purchased or harvested email lists. We offer commercial email recipients the opportunity to opt-out of further communications in every email. If you want to stop receiving commercial emails, promotional or other marketing materials, you can do so at any time by contacting ERE Media at [privacy@ere.net](mailto:privacy@ere.net).

##### 8\. NON-US USERS

The ERE Media Products are operated in and provided from the United States. If you are located in Canada, the European Union or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the ERE Media Products, participating in any of our services and/or providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.

##### 9\. CALIFORNIA AND CANADIAN USERS

Under the California “Shine The Light” law, California residents may opt-out of the disclosure of personal information to third parties for the third parties’ direct marketing purposes.  Canadian residents also have certain rights to know how their information may be shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes.  As detailed above, you may contact us for such information or to opt-out of the sharing of your personal information with third parties for marketing purposes at any time by sending an e-mail stating this preference and including your full name and e-mail address to [privacy@ere.net](mailto:privacy@ere.net).  Please note that this opt-out does not prohibit disclosure for non-marketing purposes.

##### 10\. EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA USERS – YOUR DATA PROTECTION RIGHTS UNDER GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATION (GDPR)

The General Data Protection Regulation, effective May 25, 2018, gives requires that certain information and certain rights be provided to residents of the European Union, as follows.

**Transferring Personal Information From The EU To The US.** ERE Media has its headquarters in the United States. Information we collect from you will be processed in the United States. The United States has not sought nor received a finding of “adequacy” from the European Union under Article 45 of the GDPR. ERE Media relies on derogations for specific situations as set forth in Article 49 of the GDPR. In particular, ERE Media collects and transfers to the U.S. personal information only (a) with your consent, (b) to perform a contract with you, or (c) to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of ERE Media in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. ERE Media endeavors to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal information and to use it only consistent with your relationship with ERE Media and the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**You May Elect Not To Provide Personal Information**.  You may choose not to provide ERE Media with your personal information. However, if you choose not to provide your personal information, you may not be able to enjoy the full range of services which ERE Media offers.

**How to Exercise Your Rights**.  If you reside in the European Economic Area, you have certain rights to the personal information that we have collected about you. To exercise your rights to your personal information, please contact ERE at [privacy@ere.net](mailto:privacy@ere.net).  We will respond to reasonable requests as soon as practicable, and in any event, within the time limits prescribed by law.  You have the following rights:

(a) Right Of Access To Your Personal Information: You have the right to ask us for confirmation on whether we are processing your personal information, and access to the personal information and related information on that processing (for example, the purposes of the processing, or the categories of personal information involved).

(b) Right to Correction: You have the right to have your personal information corrected.

(c) Right to Erasure: You have the right to ask us to delete your personal information. This right may be exercised, among other times: when your personal information is no longer necessary for the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise processed; when you withdraw consent on which processing is based and where there is no other legal ground for processing; when you object to processing and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing; or when your personal information has been unlawfully processed.

(d) Right To Restriction Of Processing: You have the right to request the limiting of our processing under limited circumstances, including: when the accuracy of your personal information is contested; when the processing is unlawful and you oppose the erasure of your personal information and request the restriction of the use of your personal information instead; or when you have objected to processing pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of ERE Media override your grounds.

(e) Right To Data Portability: You have the right to receive the personal information that you have provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format, and you have the right to transmit that information to another controller, including to have it transmitted directly, where technically feasible.

(f) Right To Object: You have the right to object to our processing of your personal information, as permitted by law. This right is limited to processing based on GDPR Art. 6(1)(e) or (f), and includes profiling based on those provisions, and processing for direct marketing purposes, after which we will no longer process your personal information unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing that override your interests, rights and freedoms or for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims.

**Right To Lodge A Complaint Before The Data Protection Authority.   **We encourage you to contact us directly and allow us to work with you to address your concerns. Nevertheless, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a competent data protection supervisory authority, in particular in the EU Member State where you reside, work or the place of the alleged infringement. You have the right to do so if you consider that the processing of personal information relating to you infringes applicable data protection laws.

##### 11\. SECURITY

The security of the ERE Media Products and your information is of great importance to ERE Media. ERE Media has reasonable security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of your information under ERE Media’s control, but we make no assurances about our ability to prevent any such loss, misuse or alteration, and we shall have no liability to you or any third party from any loss, misuse or alteration. We do not warrant that your access to the ERE Media Products is completely secure. You should promptly notify ERE Media if your account, username or password have been lost or stolen. ERE Media will never ask you for your password. If you need a new user name and/or password, ERE Media will generate a new username and password automatically through its computers and send it to your e-mail.

ERE Media shall notify any user whose information is suspected of being accessed, disclosed, altered or deleted by an unauthorized person, so that the user can take appropriate measures to minimize the adverse effect of such a data security breach (a “Breach Notification”). ERE Media will make such Breach Notification soon after it learns of a breach, unless it deems, at its sole discretion, that such Notification might hinder and prevent ongoing efforts to detect the source of the breach. For the avoidance of doubt, a Breach Notification does NOT constitute an admission by ERE Media that the breach occurred as a result of malpractice, failure, bad faith or negligence on behalf of ERE Media or that the breach even occurred in ERE Media’s systems.

##### 12\. CHILDREN’S PRIVACY

Protecting the privacy of children is especially important.  ERE Media does not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from anyone under the age of 13 or knowingly allow such persons to use the ERE Media Products.  If we become aware that we have collected personal information from a child under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information.

##### 13\. GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of New Jersey, without regard to its conflict of laws provisions. Any dispute arising under or in relation to this Policy shall be resolved in accordance with the terms and procedures set forth in the [Terms of Service](https://www.eremedia.com/terms-of-service/?_ga=2.182062183.1727798612.1526435550-1463628153.1526435544).

##### 14\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on this page to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.  Please check this page on a consistent basis.

##### 15\. CONTACTING ERE MEDIA

Please contact ERE Media if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of ERE Media or your dealings with the Web Sites.  You can contact us by email to [privacy@ere.net](mailto:privacy@ere.net) or by postal mail to ERE Media, Inc., 215 Thompson Street, Suite 202, New York, NY 10012.
